<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>File 1</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="file1.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sirensquid/collegeofomens/master/user-danielle/file1.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Circle of Omens" type="Sub Class" source="GM Binder" id="ID_DRUID_OMENS">
    <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Witches, sages, seers, and oracles. All of these and more are examples of those gathered in the Circle of Omens: 
	      a congregation of druids who use their powers to interpret nature's signs and proclaim to all who can hear what they mean. 
	      They use all manner of tools in their pursuit of divination, from rune-engraved knuckle bones to gem inlaid sticks to even the entrails of slain creatures.</p>
 
    </description>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_druid">
    <prerequisite>Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
    <requirements>([wis:13])</requirements>
    <setters>
        <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
        <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
    </rules>
</multiclass>
		
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
    <description level="2">Minor Omen
At 2nd level, you gain the power to dispense minor prophecies. You speak your omens, using a bonus action to impose advantage or disadvantage on the next ability check a creature within 60 feet that can hear you makes within the next minute.

Unwilling creatures can make a Wisdom saving throw against your druid spell save DC to avoid the minor
omen's effects.

Once you use this feature, you can't do so
again until finishing a short or long rest</description>
    <description level="6">A bonus of {{wisdom:modifier}} to healing and damage with spells.</description>
			<description level="2">Prognosticate
Also at 2nd level, you learn how to read and
interpret omens around you, from migratory bird
movements to leftover ash and embers from last
night's campfire.

After finishing a long rest, you can read the signs and omens around you, interpreting the will of fate for the
day. When you do so, roll 1d3. You gain the
following effects depending on the roll:

Good Omens (1). You and up to 6 other creatures
of your choice that you know and are on the same plane
of existence as you can roll 1d3 and add the result to their attack rolls ability checks, and saving throws.

Bad Omens (2). You and up to 6 other creatures
of your choice that you know and are on the same
plane of existence as you must roll 1d3 and
subtract the result to their attack rolls,
ability checks, and saving throws.

Mixed Omens (3). You and up to 6 other creatures
of your choice that you know and are on the
same plane of existence as you must reroll their
attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws
when they roll a 1, 10, or 20 on the d20. Affected
creatures must use the new roll.
You can manifest Prognosticate's effects for up to 1 hour, all at once or in shorter bursts. 
You use an action to activate the effects of your rolled omens, each time using at least 10 minutes from the remaining duration.
Affected creatures are vaguely aware of the effects of this feature, but are not alerted to its source. 
Unwilling targets can make a Wisdom saving throw against your druid spell save DC, avoiding the effects of your prognostication on a success.</description>
			<description level="6">Haruspicy
Starting at 6th level, you can divine snippets of the future through a practice called haruspicy.

You can cast divination without expending a spell slot and without preparing the spell, provided you use the corpse of a Small or larger creature that has died within the last hour as its material components. When cast this way, this spell doesn't consume the corpse nor does it contact a divine being; instead, you divine the answer to your query by reading the omens in the entrails of said corpse. You cannot use the same corpse for subsequent castings of divination this way.

You can cast this spell this way a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses after finishing a long rest.</description>
			<description level="10">Visionary
At 10th level, your powers of prophecy grow more potent.

Prognosticate now has a maximum duration of 2 hours, instead of 1.

Additionally, you can use Prognosticate as a bonus action. 
You can do so a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining expended uses after finishing a long rest.</description>
			<description level="14">Potent Prophet
At 14th level, you gain the ability to tap into fate itself, allowing you to dispense favorable and ill omens at your discretion.
You can cast bane and bless at their lowest level without expending spell slots and without preparing the spells.
When cast using this feature, targets must add your Wisdom modifier to the result of the d4 roll used by both spells if they are affected by your Prognosticate.
Additionally, you can choose to expend a use of Wild Shape when casting either spell to forgo maintaining concentration on them.
				The spell's duration remains the same.</description>

             </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="strength" value="2" />      
    </rules>
  </element>
	
</elements>
